Raymond Pearl Papers ca.1895-1940 Mss.B.P312
American Philosophical Society
- Series IV. Bound Volumes (Box 34-40)
  Diaries, manuscripts, notebooks, scrapbooks, and scientific "commonplace books" of Raymond Pearl. The diaries consist of very brief daily entries with relatively little detail.
  Biographical and personal data; Business; Eugenics; Human genetics; Physiology -- Alcohol, tobacco; Physiology -- Longevity; Political issues; Population, demography; Publication; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements; World War II -- Impact on science
  - Scrapbook: Volume 1, Pages 1-50, 1922-1925; 50.0 p. (Box 34)
  - Scrapbook: Volume 1, Pages 51-100, 1922-1925; 50.0 p. (Box 34)
  - Scrapbook: Volume 1, Pages 101-146, 1922-1925; 46.0 p. (Box 34)
  - Scrapbook: Volume 2, Pages 1-25, 1923-1926; 25.0 p. (Box 34)
  - Scrapbook: Volume 3, Pages 1-50, 1919-1927; 50.0 p. (Box 34)
  - Scrapbook: Volume 3, Pages 51-100, 1919-1927; 50.0 p. (Box 34)
  - Scrapbook: Volume 3, Pages 101-148, 1919-1927; 48.0 p. (Box 34)
  - Scrapbook: Volume 4, Pages 1-50, 1938-1939; 50.0 p. (Box 35)
  - Scrapbook: Volume 4, Pages 51-100, 1938-1939; 50.0 p. (Box 35)
  - Scrapbook: Volume 4, Pages 101-146, 1938-1939; 46.0 p. (Box 35)
  - Scrapbook: Volume 4a, Pages 1-50, 1926-1928; 50.0 p. (Box 35)
  - Scrapbook: Volume 4a, Pages 51-100, 1926-1928; 50.0 p. (Box 35)
  - Scrapbook: Volume 4a, Pages 101-148, 1926-1928; 48.0 p. (Box 35)
  - Scrapbook: Volume 5, Pages 1-50, 1928-1929; 50.0 p. (Box 36)
  - Scrapbook: Volume 5, Pages 51-100, 1928-1929; 50.0 p. (Box 36)
  - Scrapbook: Volume 5, Pages 101-148, 1928-1929; 48.0 p. (Box 36)
  - Scrapbook: Volume 6, Pages 1-50, 1930-1933; 50.0 p. (Box 36)
  - Scrapbook: Volume 6, Pages 51-100, 1930-1933; 50.0 p. (Box 36)
  - Scrapbook: Volume 6, Pages 101-150, 1930-1933; 50.0 p. (Box 36)
  - Scrapbook: Volume 7, Pages 1-50, 1934-1935; 50.0 p. (Box 36)
  - Scrapbook: Volume 7, Pages 51-100, 1934-1935; 50.0 p. (Box 37)
  - Scrapbook: Volume 7, Pages 101-148, 1934-1935; 48.0 p. (Box 37)
  - Scrapbook: Volume 8, Pages 1-48, 1936-1938; 48.0 p. (Box 37)
  - Scrapbook: Volume 8, Pages 49-83, 1936-1938; 35.0 p. (Box 37)
  - Scrapbook: Volume 8, Pages 84-99, 1936-1938; 16.0 p. (Box 37)
  - Scrapbook: Volume 8, Pages 100-125, 1936-1938; 26.0 p. (Box 37)
  - Scrapbook: Volume 8, Pages 126-146, 1936-1938; 21.0 p. (Box 37)
  - Scrapbook: Volume 9, Pages 1-24, 1939-1940; 24.0 p. (Box 37)
  - Scrapbook: Volume 9, Pages 25-48, 1939-1940; 24.0 p. (Box 37)
  - Scrapbook: Volume 9, Pages 49-72, 1939-1940; 24.0 p. (Box 37)
  - Scrapbook: Volume 9, Pages 73-84, 1939-1940; 12.0 p. (Box 37)
  - Scrapbook: Volume 9, Pages 85-100, 1939-1940; 16.0 p. (Box 37)
  - Scrapbook: Volume 9, Pages 101-116, 1939-1940; 16.0 p. (Box 37)
  - Scrapbook: Volume 9, Pages 117-148, 1939-1940; 32.0 p. (Box 37)
  - Scrapbook: Volume 10, Sympathy Telegrams, 1940 (Box 37)
  - Scrapbook: Volume 10, Pages 1-24, 1940; 24.0 p. (Box 37)
  - Scrapbook: Volume 10, Pages 25-39, 1940; 15.0 p. (Box 37)
  - Problem of Human Fertility (Manuscript) - Chapter I, n.d. (Box 38)
  - Problem of Human Fertility (Manuscript) - Chapter II, n.d. (Box 38)
  - Problem of Human Fertility (Manuscript) - Chapter III, n.d. (Box 38)
  - Rate of Living (Manuscript) - Chapter I-II, n.d. (Box 38)
  - Rate of Living (Manuscript) - Chapter III, n.d. (Box 38)
  - Rate of Living (Manuscript) - Chapter IV, n.d. (Box 38)
  - Rate of Living (Manuscript) - Chapter V, n.d. (Box 38)
  - Rate of Living (Manuscript) - Chapter VIII, n.d. (Box 38)
  - Rate of Living (Manuscript) - Further Data on the Measurement of Inherent Validity, n.d. (Box 38)
  - Rate of Living (Manuscript) - Appendix I, II (Box 38)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, n.d.; 12 folders (Box 38)
  - Subject Headings for Notes, n.d. (Box 39)
  - I. Population - Notes, n.d. (Box 39)
  - II. Foods, Feeding Habits - Notes, n.d. (Box 39)
  - III. Evolution, Prehistoy, Archeology - Notes, n.d. (Box 39)
  - IV. The Environment, Geology, Forestry - Notes, n.d. (Box 39)
  - V. Migration - Notes, n.d. (Box 39)
  - VI. Mortality and Morbidity - Notes, 2 folders (Box 39)
  - VII. Fertility, Fecundity, Marriage, Divorce, Birth Control, Sex - Notes (Box 39)
  - VIII. Psychology and Psychiatry; Religion - Notes (Box 39)
  - IX. Animal Behavior - Notes, n.d. (Box 39)
  - X. History, Biography, Anecdotes - Notes, n.d. (Box 39)
  - XI. Sociology and Economics - Notes (Box 39)
  - XII. Ethnology - Notes, n.d. (Box 39)
  - XIII. Physical Anthropology - Notes, n.d. (Box 39)
  - XIV. Physiology - Notes, n.d. (Box 40)
  - XV. Longevity, Senescence, Senility - Notes, n.d. (Box 40)
  - XVI. Biometry and Statistics - Notes (Box 40)
  - XVII. Heredity - Notes, n.d. (Box 40)
  - XVIII. Education - Notes, n.d. (Box 40)
  - XIX. Miscellaneous - Notes, n.d. (Box 40)
  - Diaries, 1902; 1 vol.; Pearl, Raymond, 1879-1940
  - Diaries, 1903; 1 vol.; Pearl, Raymond, 1879-1940
  - Diaries, 1909; 1 vol.; Pearl, Raymond, 1879-1940
  - Diaries, 1910; 1 vol.; Pearl, Raymond, 1879-1940
  - Diaries, 1911; 1 vol.; Pearl, Raymond, 1879-1940
  - Diaries, 1912; 1 vol.; Pearl, Raymond, 1879-1940
  - Diaries, 1913; 1 vol.; Pearl, Raymond, 1879-1940
  - Diaries, 1914; 1 vol.; Pearl, Raymond, 1879-1940
  - Diaries, 1916; 1 vol.; Pearl, Raymond, 1879-1940
  - Diaries, 1917; 1 vol.; Pearl, Raymond, 1879-1940
  - Diaries, 1920; 1 vol.; Pearl, Raymond, 1879-1940
  - Diaries, 1920; 1 vol.; Pearl, Raymond, 1879-1940
  - Diaries, 1921; 1 vol.; Pearl, Raymond, 1879-1940
  - Diaries, 1922; 1 vol.; Pearl, Raymond, 1879-1940
  - Diaries, 1923; 1 vol.; Pearl, Raymond, 1879-1940
  - Diaries, 1924; 1 vol.; Pearl, Raymond, 1879-1940
  - Diaries, 1925; 1 vol.; Pearl, Raymond, 1879-1940
  - Diaries, 1926; 1 vol.; Pearl, Raymond, 1879-1940
  - Diaries, 1927; 1 vol.; Pearl, Raymond, 1879-1940
  - Diaries, 1928; 1 vol.; Pearl, Raymond, 1879-1940
  - Diaries, 1929; 1 vol.; Pearl, Raymond, 1879-1940
  - Diaries, 1930; 1 vol.; Pearl, Raymond, 1879-1940
  - Diaries, 1931; 1 vol.; Pearl, Raymond, 1879-1940
  - Diaries, 1932; 1 vol.; Pearl, Raymond, 1879-1940
  - Diaries, 1933; 1 vol.; Pearl, Raymond, 1879-1940
  - Diaries, 1934; 1 vol.; Pearl, Raymond, 1879-1940
  - Diaries, 1935; 1 vol.; Pearl, Raymond, 1879-1940
  - Diaries, 1936; 1 vol.; Pearl, Raymond, 1879-1940
  - Diaries, 1937; 1 vol.; Pearl, Raymond, 1879-1940
  - Diaries, 1938; 1 vol.; Pearl, Raymond, 1879-1940
  - Diaries, 1939; 1 vol.; Pearl, Raymond, 1879-1940
  - Diaries, 1940; 1 vol.; Pearl, Raymond, 1879-1940
  - Laboratory notebook, 1930; 1 vol.; Pearl, Raymond, 1879-1940
    Bibliographical matters; Statistics, biostatistics, biometrics
  - Laboratory notebook, 1931; 1 vol.; Pearl, Raymond, 1879-1940
  - Commonplace book, 1925; 1 vol.; Pearl, Raymond, 1879-1940
  - Commonplace book, 1926; 1 vol.; Pearl, Raymond, 1879-1940
  - Problem book, 1921 May 14-1923 January 1; 5 vols.; Pearl, Raymond, 1879-1940
  - Unlabeled notebook, 1929-1937; 1 vol.; Pearl, Raymond, 1879-1940
    Includes quotations from letters (1932-1937) re: laboratory work
  - Unlabeled diary, 1918 October-December; 1 vol.; Pearl, Raymond, 1879-1940
  - Unlabeled notebook, 1916; 1 vol.; Pearl, Raymond, 1879-1940
    Includes "Memorandum of conversation with Dr. W. H. Welch at Maryland club, Balto., Nov. 18, 1916
  - Notes, 1917 October 10-12; 3 leaves; Pearl, Raymond, 1879-1940
  - Unlabeled diary, 1905 September 28-October 8; 1 vol.; Pearl, Raymond, 1879-1940
  - Unlabeled diary, 1924?, 1927?; 1 vol.; Pearl, Raymond, 1879-1940
  - Unlabeled diary, 1928? July-August; 1 vol.; Pearl, Raymond, 1879-1940
- Series V. Photographs (Box 40)
  Miscellaneous formal and informal photographs depicting Pearl and his associates throughout his career. In addition to a few portraits of Pearl there is an image of researchers at the Maine Biological Laboratory, 1897, and one taken at the dinner at the 10th Annual Meeting of the American Association of Physical Anthropologists held in honor of the 70th birthday of Ales Hrdlicka.
  - Raymond Pearl (reading at desk). [in his 40s-50s?], 1.
    - a) B/w print., 2 1/2" x 3 1/2".
    - b) B/w print., 8" x 10".
  - "Breeze Brow"? Clapboard house with 2 women on lawn. Brown (Sienna) print [picture postcard]., 2.; 3 1/2" x 5 1/2".
  - "Our First Residence in Orono [Maine]." Clapboard house with 3 figures on walk. Brown (Sienna) print [picture postcard]., 3.; 3 1/2" x 5 1/2".
  - "W.H.W. at the Monument of Brillat-Savarin, inaugurales? the 11 Sept. 1927. Dr. Raymond Pearl from A.C.?K." B/w print., 4.; 3 1/2" x 5 1/2".
  - Raymond Pearl. [Portrait]. [in his 40s-50s?], 5.
    - a) B/w print (seems brown)., 5" x 7".
    - b) B/w print or engraving., 8 1/2" x 11 1/2". 8 copies.
  - Raymond Pearl. [Portrait]. B/w print (seems brown). 5" x 7". [in his 20s-30s?], 6.
  - Raymond Pearl. [Portrait]. [in his 30s-40s?]., 7.
    - a) B/w print., 7" x 10".
    - b) B/w print., 4 3/4" x 6 3/4".
  - "Advisory Board. School of Public Health." Group photo. B/w print. 8" x 10". 11 men seated at a long table in a library. Raymond Pearl is 4th from the left., 8.
  - "M[aine] B[iological] L[aboratory] Investigators, 1897. 8077." Group photo. B/w print. 7 1/2" x 9 1/2" mounted on 10" x 11" board (damaged). [Pearl does not appear to be in the photograph]., 9.
  - "Schouw-wand met Deur" [Chimney-wall with Door]. B/w print. 7" x 9" mounted on 10 1/2" x 12 1/2" board. Fireplace, door, and desk in Dutch living room., 10.
  - "Dinner of the Tenth Annual Meeting of the American Association of Physical Anthropologists, in Honour of the 70th Birthday of Ales Hrdlicka, Philadelphia, April 4, 1939.", 1939 April 4; 11.; 1" tear on right edge.; Group of men and women, seated at table for Association of Physical Anthropologists; Raymond Pearl is at the head table, 5th from the right.
  - "American Statistical Association. 100th Anniversary Dinner. M.I.T. November 27, 1939." Group photo. B/w print. 6 1/2" x 16 1/2". Raymond Pearl at center of head table above flowers (middle-top of photo.)., 12.
  - Raymond Pearl in suit. [in his 40s-50s?], 13.
    - a) B/w print., 3" x 4".
    - b) B/w print., 4" x 6". (2 copies of 13a
  - Raymond Pearl (laughing). B/w print. 5" x 6 1/2" (fallen off its 8" x 10" mount). [Not well focused. Possibly an enlarged detail of another photograph?]., 14.
  - Unidentified group photo. on the steps of a large building. B/w print. 13" x 16 1/2". "By S. Chickering [or Schickering] 1907." 1" tear on right edge., 15.
- Series VI. Certificates, 1903-1940, n.d.; 2 folders (Box 40)
  - Certificates, 1903-1940, n.d. (Box 40)
  - Diplomas, 1919, 1935, n.d. (Box 40)